<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-27T19:40:43+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">sam is fierce</title><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">What Sustainability Means to Me</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/25/what-sustainability-means-to-me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Sustainability Means to Me" /><published>2018-09-25T00:44:03+00:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T00:44:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/25/what-sustainability-means-to-me</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/25/what-sustainability-means-to-me/">&lt;p&gt;I grew up in a Midwest, meat and potatoes house. We ate red meat multiple times a week, never bought organic food (it was too expensive), drove huge cars and only recycled when it was convenient for us (which, honestly, wasn’t often). We only talked about the environment on Earth Day; it was never something I was taught to care about. Yet, over the past few years, something changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it started when I moved to Los Angeles. With the seemingly-never-ending drought in Southern California, many of my friends and colleagues talked about water usage - something I had never thought twice about while living in a state surrounded by giant lakes. It was the first time that I was confronted with the reality that our natural resources aren’t endless. I’m not sure if I started caring because I wanted to blend in or because it was something I truly cared about, but regardless, it changed me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180925/balilitteredbeach.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since then, I’ve had the opportunity to travel the world and, as a result, I’ve been exposed to more than my younger-mind could have imagined. In the US we embrace the idea of excess and waste is hidden from us; therefore we don’t think twice about over-indulging or throwing things out. In many other countries, that’s not the case. In South East Asia, there was a pungent, acrid smell that seemed to pervade the air. I later found out that it was because locals had no choice but to burn their trash. When walking picturesque beaches, I was disappointed to see trash washing up everywhere. In small villages, I saw a level of poverty I had never been exposed to in the US. And, the worst, was the countless acts of animal cruelty that I saw everywhere. It breaks my heart to imagine what happens behind closed doors in the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I’m far from perfect, traveling has taught me to appreciate and embrace sustainability. What does that mean though? It’s such a broad term that is used by many people to cover many topics. For me, it means living a life that has a positive impact on the environment, economy and community. I break this idea into two main pieces: environmentally conscious and community conscious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Environmentally Conscious&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180925/tanzanialion.jpg&quot; /&gt;
I think this one is pretty simple, but basically, it just means that I try to live a life that keeps the environment in mind. This means wasting less, recycling/reusing more and being more animal-friendly. I’ve recently gone pescatarian (I haven’t been able to make the full jump to veganism or even vegetarian, yet), which feels like a more ethical choice for me. When I do buy animal products (such as eggs or milk), I look for items that are organic, free-range and cruelty-free. When I buy coffee, I look for beans that are shade grown or bird friendly, as it means that the coffee farm isn’t cutting down trees to make more room for coffee plants. I’ve started reading a lot more labels and doing more research before and during shopping trips. I also try to stay at eco-friendly hotels, do tours that support the environment and avoid animal activities (more often than not the animals are mistreated). Overall, I’ve become a lot more aware of how my actions can impact the world around me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Community Conscious&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180925/tanzaniavillage.jpg&quot; /&gt;
This might be a term I made up, but, for me, part of living a sustainable lifestyle means living a life that supports local communities and economies. I keep this in mind when I’m home and when I’m traveling. At home, I try to shop at local stores and farmers markets, avoid big-box retailers and visit local restaurants. When I’m traveling, I support locals by going on local-run tours and activities (that are environmentally friendly, of course), staying at boutique hotels and shopping at places where the goods are locally made. While I am sometimes a sucker for typical tourist hotspots, I do what I can to embrace and support local culture by finding off-the-beaten-path spots and destinations. No matter where I am, I try to support the local community with my dollars (and voice), therefore empowering local entrepreneurs, protecting their environments and valuing their culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d love to hear your thoughts on sustainability. What does it mean to you? Are there any major topics that I missed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180925/samisfierce_pinterest_whatsustainabilitymeanstome.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><category term="sustainability" /><summary type="html">Sustainability means different things to different people, but I wanted to take a second and share with you what it means to me. It's more than just eco-friendly; it's making a positive impact on the world.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20180925/sustainability_balifield.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Beyond My Wildest Dreams - Two Weeks in Tanzania</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/08/29/ultimate-tanzania-guide/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beyond My Wildest Dreams - Two Weeks in Tanzania" /><published>2018-08-29T00:44:03+00:00</published><updated>2018-08-29T00:44:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/08/29/ultimate-tanzania-guide</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/08/29/ultimate-tanzania-guide/">&lt;p&gt;Despite one of the worst travel days of my life (including two flight cancellations, two flight delays, four rebookings, a four hour drive to JFK at 3am and lost luggage), my recent trip to Tanzania was one of the most amazing travel experiences I’ve ever had. If it’s on your bucket list (and it should be), I highly recommend getting it on your calendar. Below, I’ve shared my itinerary and tips for when you’re ready to make your wildest dreams come true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Before you go:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Money: Most places in Tanzania accept USD, however, they only accept crisp, new bills so be sure to get new cash from the bank before heading out. The local currency is shillings (you can check the conversion rates &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.xe.com/currencyconverter/convert/?Amount=1&amp;amp;From=USD&amp;amp;To=TZS&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), but we rarely had to use them. I would recommend getting some out though if you plan on buying a lot as some of the really smaller shops don’t always have USD on them. It’s also worth noting that most places (including hotels) charge 5% for credit card transactions. If you’re planning on having any larger purchases once you’re there (including hotel stays), I’d recommend having cash on hand to cover it as that 5% can quickly add up.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Visa: Americans can secure a Visa on Arrival when they land in Tanzania. Be warned, this is $100 and you must pay cash (make sure you have crisp, new bills on hand!) when going through customs. If you’re not from the US, be sure to check the visa requirements online prior to taking off.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power: Like most other countries, Tanzania has 220 volt electricity. If you’re from the US or another country with a different voltage, your laptop, phone, camera and any other chargers you have SHOULD be fine, but this will impact your ability to use things such as blow dryers, steamers, straighteners, and so on. If you plan on using any of these items, make sure they’re either compatible with 220V or buy a power converter to ensure you can use them safely. The last time I used a US blow dryer in a 220V socket, it basically turned into a blow torch and I almost lit my head on fire. You’ve been warned.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Travel vaccinations: Before traveling to Tanzania I picked up a prescription for Malaria pills and had the yellow fever vaccine. The Yellow Fever vaccine is REQUIRED when entering Tanzania from a country that has a risk of Yellow Fever (such as Ethiopia), so make sure you consult your doctor and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://wwwnc.cdc.gov/travel/destinations/traveler/none/tanzania&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;CDC website&lt;/a&gt; prior to your trip to make sure you’re prepared for your trip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When to go: Tanzania’s busy season aligns with it’s dry season: June through October (or so), however I would recommend going in the shoulder months of May or November. The weather is nice (although you may experience a brief shower or two), the parks are less crowded and there is more wildlife since there’s more vegetation. If you’re lucky, you might even get to see the Great Migration!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Days 1: Arrive at JRO&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180608/dayonetanzania.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Tanzanian safari requires a lot of time on the road. Try and schedule your first day to only be a few hours of driving so you can get a good night’s sleep. Our first day we drove to Karatu (about three hours from the airport), the last town before the Ngorongoro Conservation Area. I’d recommend staying at either &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/tz/olea-africana-lodge.html?aid=1491966&amp;amp;no_rooms=1&amp;amp;group_adults=1&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Olea Africana Lodge&lt;/a&gt; or, if you’re able to splurge, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/tz/arusha-coffee-lodge.en.html?aid=1491966&amp;amp;no_rooms=1&amp;amp;group_adults=1&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Arusha Coffee Lodge&lt;/a&gt;. This is where &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.shanga.org/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Shanga&lt;/a&gt; is located - it’s an amazing shop that employs locally disabled individuals to create unique, high-qualtiy, handmade jewellery, glassware and homeware using recycled materials. You should definitely check it out if you’re in Arusha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Day 2-3: The Ngorongoro Crater&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180608/ngorongorocrater.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Ngorongoro Crater was formed when a giant volcano (thought to be larger than Kilimanjaro!) exploded and then collapsed on itself nearly three million years ago. Today, the crater is one of the world’s most astonishing places, filled with lush vegetation and wildlife. As home to the black rhino, lions, elephants, leopards and cougars - it’s one of the best places in the world to see the Big Five. It is a bit chilly though, so I definitely recommend wearing layers while you’re there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Where to stay&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;:
For a cultural and rustic experience, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ngorongoro.cc/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Ngorongoro Rhino Lodge&lt;/a&gt;. The grounds are amazing and decorated with local art. Another gorgeously rustic lodge is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/tz/ngorongoro-sopa-lodge.en.html?aid=1491966&amp;amp;no_rooms=1&amp;amp;group_adults=1&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Ngorongoro Sopa Lodge&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Days 4-6: The Serengeti National Park&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180608/serengetinationalpark.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Serengeti is one of the most well known safari destinations and it did not disappoint. Here, we were able to see four of the big five (everything except the Black Rhino) along with countless zebras, wildebeest, giraffes, hippos and more. Everywhere we looked we saw animals lounging, playing, fighting and eating. The park is huge and I’d recommend spending at least two full days exploring it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where to stay:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed at &lt;a href=&quot;https://shuhudiaadventurecamp.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Suhudia Adventure Camp&lt;/a&gt; and it was an amazing glamping experience. We had our own luxury tents (complete with showers) and were treated to delicious gourment food. I’d highly recommend it. I’ve also heard great things about &amp;lt;a href=”https://www.booking.com/hotel/tz/serengeti-serena-safari-lodge.en.html?aid=1491966&amp;amp;no_rooms=1&amp;amp;group_adults=1” target=”blank&amp;gt;Serena Safari Lodge&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Days 7-9: Tarangire National Park&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180608/tarangire.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tarangire National Park is a hidden gem in Tanzania! We only spent a day here, but we were quickly impressed with the beauty and quiet of the park. The park was filled with gorgeous wildflowers, and while some of the animals had already migrated, we still saw quite a bit of wildlife. The only downside of this park was that we ran into hundreds of murderous flies. If you do decide to go here in May, be prepared for fly bites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where to stay:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twctanzania.com/en/accommodation/lake-burunge-tented-camp/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Lake Burunge Tented Camp&lt;/a&gt; and it was probably one of my favorite places we stayed! I would highly recommend it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Days 10-11: Pingwe, Zanzibar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180608/zanzibar.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a week of dusty roads and safari clothes, it was so nice to spend some time in the tropics. Zanzibar is a unique and beautiful island with gorgeous, sandy beaches. We opted to stay by the beach for our first few nights and it was amazing to do nothing and just relax. I highly recommend visiting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.therockrestaurantzanzibar.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;The Rock&lt;/a&gt; while on that side of the island. It’s a gorgeous and unique restaurant situated on a, you guessed it, rock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where to stay:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/tz/kichanga-lodge.en.html?aid=1491966&amp;amp;no_rooms=1&amp;amp;group_adults=1&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Kichanga Lodge&lt;/a&gt; and had an amazing time. The staff were kind and helpful, the beach was beautiful and the food was delicious. To warn you though, there is no air conditioning, and I recommend getting a room with a high ceiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Days 12-14: Stone Town, Zanzibar&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180608/stonetown.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the beautiful beaches, Zanzibar has an amazing amount of culture and history. Stone Town is a great place to visit to get a taste of the island’s past. It’s very walkable as long as you don’t mind twisting alleyways and a short drive from the airport. While there, definitely buy spices from Darajani Market, have dinner at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.emersonspice.com/tea-house/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Emerson Spice Tea House&lt;/a&gt;, tour the night market at Forodhani Gardens and take a boat out to the sand bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Where to stay:&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stayed at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.booking.com/hotel/tz/jafferji-house-amp-spa.en.html?aid=1491966&amp;amp;no_rooms=1&amp;amp;group_adults=1&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Jafferji House&lt;/a&gt; and absolu tely loved it. It was one of the most unique properties we stayed at and was filled with amazing local artwork and photography.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, our time in Tanzania was surreal; filled with natural beauty, awe-inspiring wildlife and kind souls. It was a trip that changed me and the way that I think about cultures and our world and I cannot wait to go back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you been to Tanzania? I’d love to hear about your experiences in the comments!
&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180608/tanzania_pinterest.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bloglovin.com/blog/19606913/?claim=xuzcd94scd3&quot;&gt;Follow my blog with Bloglovin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><category term="tanzania" /><summary type="html">The perfect Tanzania travel guide for those who want to experience all that Tanzania and Zanzibar has to offer.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20180608/traveltanzania.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">10 Tips to Hit 10K on Instagram</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/work/2018/05/02/ten-tips-10k/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="10 Tips to Hit 10K on Instagram" /><published>2018-05-02T00:44:03+00:00</published><updated>2018-05-02T00:44:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/work/2018/05/02/ten-tips-10k</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/work/2018/05/02/ten-tips-10k/">&lt;p&gt;For many of us just starting out, 10K is an elusive and exciting number. It’s the number that finally gets you a K next to your follower count and unlocks the exciting “swipe up” feature on your instagram stories. But, it’s a challenging number to reach. I’ve spent countless hours on instagram liking, commenting and following until I finally hit that exciting number yesterday. Many of you have asked how I did it and, rather than waiting to hit 100K or more to write a how-to post, I thought I would share my entire journey with you, starting now. Below are my 10 tips on getting your first 10K followers. I’d love to hear your questions and thoughts - so be sure to comment below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Engage, engage, engage&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is going to be everyone’s least favorite tip, but it’s also the most important. I spend hours (yes, HOURS - at least three but often more) on instagram every day liking, commenting and following accounts in my niche. It’s impossible for people to start following you or liking your content if they don’t know you exist. You have to put yourself out there and the best way to do that is by engaging on the platform. Leave unique comments (not “nice pic!”) and reply to people’s captions; make them feel important and they’ll likely reciprocate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not use, nor do I recommend using, bots of any kind. They are a fast track to being shadowbanned or, even worse, having your account deleted. This includes programs such as: instavast, instaq, rise social or any other solution that automatically likes, comments and follows people for you. These tools violate instagram’s T&amp;amp;Cs and access the IG API without the platform’s permission. They also make you so active that there’s a good chance you’ll end up getting blocked when you actually engage on the platform yourself. Bots seem like there’s an easy way to grow, but I do not recommend them and truly believe that brands and people can see right through them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Use all the tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180502/display-purposes.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hashtags, geotags and people tags are a great way to get your photos featured and discovered by new followers. Share your location using a geotag, the topic of the photo using hashtags, and showcase brands and feature accounts by tagging them in the photo itself. You can tag up to 20 other accounts and use up to 30 hashtags and I highly recommend taking advantage of all of these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s smart to have a good strategy for each of these tagging options. Tag feature accounts that align with the photo and use a similar aesthetic (for example, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/sheisnotlost/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;@sheisnotlost&lt;/a&gt; features light and airy travel photos and likely wouldn’t repost something that is dark and moody). If you’re wearing certain brands of clothing or using a certain product, it’s smart to tag those accounts as well as they may repost your photo. Geotags are also great because it gives you the opportunity to trend for a location and followers always appreciate knowing where your photos are taken. If you’re a small account, be more specific with your geotags (for example, Cabina Bali vs Bali, Indonesia) as there is less competition and you’re more likely to trend for something more specific. As for hashtags, make sure they’re relevant. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.displaypurposes.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Display Purposes&lt;/a&gt; is a great tool for discovering hashtags in a certain niche if you’re in a hurry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Create beautiful content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180502/samisfierce-before-after.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is another obvious one, but it’s also very important. If you want to hit 10K or more (organically), you can’t create standard photos. Each photo you post needs to be stunning. You have to shoot in good lighting (ideally golden hour), wear beautiful outfits (if you’re a fashion/style IGer that is), and have gorgeous colors. Every one thinks that instagrammers live in a magical world filled with perfect lighting and great outfits, but that’s not true. Every photo posted has been thoroughly thought out, scrupulously planned, carefully selected and then edited to perfection. In order to grow you need to create photos that you love and that others will love to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start doing this, work on your photography and editing skills. It’s great to be able to work with photographers, but that isn’t always an option and it’s good to have those skills on your own. Start focusing on getting good in Lightroom, shoot in RAW (instead of jpg) and invest in good equipment, if you can. I’ve been fortunate to work with various photographers for a lot of my shots, however, I do edit 98% of all my photos myself and am able to shoot myself if I need to. I’m not a perfect photographer or an expert in Lightroom, but I have noticed a huge difference since honing in on these skills.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;4. Develop a consistent aesthetic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a gorgeous and consistent feed makes growing your account a lot easier. There are a ton of different themes that you can use for a beautiful feed; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/aleksandrazee/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;neutral tones&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/kerifay/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;pops of red&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/charlottebridgeman/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;muted&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/modbymonique/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;hues of pink&lt;/a&gt;. There’s an endless variety of themes, it’s just about how you edit your photos and making sure they have a consistent look and feel. And, if you ever mess up by posting something that doesn’t look right, don’t be afraid to archive or delete a photo to maintain a more-consistent look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;5. Post often&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180502/tailwind-instagram-study.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The more often you post, the more likes and comments you’re going to get. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tailwindapp.com/i/samisfierce&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Tailwind&lt;/a&gt;, a visual marketing tool, did a study on over 100,000 instagram profiles and found that profiles that post seven or more times per week get more likes and followers than those that post less frequently. Posting more gives you more opportunities to trend for hashtags and geotags, and also makes it more likely that you’ll appear at the top of your followers’ timeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;6. Respond to comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time consuming and annoying, but it’s so important to respond to the comments on your photos. It allows you to start building a relationship with your followers and encourages them to continue to comment. Ask them questions and encourage them to engage with you. It’s a lot to ask to write a deep, meaningful response to every photo, and you don’t have to. Even a simple thank you will make a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;7. Plan ahead&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180502/later-app.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrambling to post a photo at the last minute doesn’t help anyone. It likely ends in you posting a lower quality photo and leaves you with a jumbled aesthetic. Planning tools help you schedule your photos and see your overall feed prior to posting. My favorite is &lt;a href=&quot;https://later.com/r/e12058&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Later&lt;/a&gt;, it allows you to plan and schedule your posts and it even has an auto-publish feature (with limitations). My favorite tool is the drag and drop preview and I am constantly using it when planning my feed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;8. Pay attention to your numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180502/switch-to-ig-business.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of people have asked me if it’s worth it to switch to a business profile. Amidst rumors of lower reach and dropping engagement numbers, people are hesitant to do so. However, I think switching to a business profile is crucial to growing your instagram account. Using a business account gives you access to demographic information, post analytics, best time of day to post, instagram ads and a contact button. If you want to work with brands, it’s extremely important to know the stats that a business profile gives you access to. Until you’re big enough for your follower count alone to warrant you receiving brand collaborations, using a data-driven approach will help you build up your portfolio and win partnership opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;9. Use Instagram stories&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instagram stories are a great way to showcase your daily life and behind-the-scenes moments. Followers love them because it gives them another way to get to know you and engage with you, thus building a stronger relationship. Plus, you can use the geotag and hashtag stickers to increase your reach and trend in new ways. I also encourage creating Highlights that further organize your stories for people who are new to your page and want to learn more about you. I currently have highlights for the destinations I’ve traveled to, style, blog, beauty and behinds the scenes moments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10. Find an instagram community&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As amazing as instagram is, it can also be extremely frustrating. You’ll likely run into slow patches, low engagement and potentially even shadowbanning. I highly recommend finding an instagram community that you can talk to and vent with when things like this happen. Whether it’s a comment/like pod, Facebook group, or curated group of friends you’ve made through the platform, having a group of people to turn to when times get tough makes things a lot easier. It’s also a good way to further your growth and meet new like-minded people. Plus, it’s great to have people to cheer you on and to join you in celebrating your victories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you think? I’d love to hear your thoughts and questions below!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180502/10tips-10k-pinterest.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;small-space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><category term="instagram" /><summary type="html">So you want to grow your instagram? Here are ten tips on how to reach 10K from someone who just got there.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20180502/ten-tips-10k.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">What to Wear and Where to Shop in Bali</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/style/2018/04/22/bali-2018-lookbook/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What to Wear and Where to Shop in Bali" /><published>2018-04-22T00:44:03+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T00:44:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/style/2018/04/22/bali-2018-lookbook</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/style/2018/04/22/bali-2018-lookbook/">&lt;p&gt;I got this &lt;span class=&quot;italics&quot;&gt;Lanikai Dress&lt;/span&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.milathelabel.com&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Mila the Label&lt;/a&gt; at their store in Seminyak. Mila the Label has a few locations in Bali (Seminyak, Canggu and Ubud) and they all have super cute pieces! I complimented the dress with a pair of retro sunnies (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~ar8Dq&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; Ray Ban’s), which I thought polished off the look.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(The dress is now sold out but &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~ar8At&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is an equally-cute alternative from Zulily!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-beachgold-bali.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.beachgoldbali.com/collections/dresses/products/faux-riviera-dress-silver&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Faux Riviera Dress from Beachgold Bali (in silver)&lt;/a&gt; became my go-to casual dress. The material was light, which meant I wasn’t dying of heat and it was casual enough for me to wear anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-indigo-luna-onepiece.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can never have enough swimsuits in Bali. I’ve spent years trying to find a one-piece that fit well before I found the &lt;a href=&quot;https://indigoluna.net/collections/one-pieces/products/ava-one-piece-mustard?variant=42263508293&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Ava One piece from Indigo Luna&lt;/a&gt;. Not only is it super comfortable, but it’s also the perfect piece for Instagram. And, did I mention that Indigo Luna uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://indigoluna.net/pages/sustainable-practices&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;recycled materials and all natural dyes&lt;/a&gt;? Win, win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-souq-wu.jpg&quot; /&gt;
This &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.souqstore.co/collections/shop/products/wu-linen-trumpet-sleeve-top-navy-white-stripes&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Wu Top&lt;/a&gt; is from my all-time favorite store/cafe in Bali, Souq. Located in Seminyak, Souq prides itself on provinding ethically sourced materials and products for their shop and produce and ingredients for their vegetables. They have tons of gorgeous home goods and clothes inspired by the world. And, their cafe has amazing cake (I highly recommend the lemon coconut). For this look, I paired the top with a high-waisted black skirt and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kokoonsilks.com/scarf/scarf-guci&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;head-scarf&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;span class=&quot;italics&quot;&gt;Kookon Silks&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-kewangen.jpg&quot; /&gt;
I couldn’t have asked for a more perfect Instagram dress than this blue stunner from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kewangen.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Kewangen&lt;/a&gt;, a small shop in Ubud. Their store is filled with lots of goodies, but if you can’t make it to Ubud &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lulus.com/products/gently-adrift-navy-blue-maxi-dress/355502.html&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Adrift Dress from Lulus&lt;/a&gt; is also super cute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-isabelle-rose-swim.jpg&quot; /&gt;
I’m a sucker for stripes and when I saw the &lt;span class=&quot;italics&quot;&gt;Avalon print from Isabella Rose Swimwear&lt;/span&gt;, I was obsessed. You can buy the bottoms &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcqj&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the top &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcqm&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. It also comes in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcqO&quot;&gt;bralette cut&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcqR&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;one-shoulder cut&lt;/a&gt; and in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcqV&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;high-waist&lt;/a&gt; option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-mila-the-label-bali.jpg&quot; /&gt;
My ABSOLUTE favorite dress from Bali. I could probably do an entire blog post just of photos of me wearing this dress (like &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BfyDNltlmhE/?taken-by=samisfierce&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;this photo&lt;/a&gt; of me at &lt;a href=&quot;http://opiabali.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Opia Bali&lt;/a&gt;). This is the &lt;span class=&quot;italics&quot;&gt;Gaya Maxi Dress&lt;/span&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.milathelabel.com/collections/dresses/products/gaya-maxi-dress&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Mila the Label&lt;/a&gt;. Sadly, it’s now sold out, but this &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palma-australia.com/collections/dresses/products/pm1595-stella-ruffle-maxi-dress-2&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Stella Ruffle Maxi Dress&lt;/a&gt; is a great alternative from Palma Autralia (which also has a shop in Bali).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-shein-yellow.jpg&quot; /&gt;
When you go to Bali, you have to bring an “Instagram Dress”. And this &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcM4&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;yellow high-low piece&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;span class=&quot;italics&quot;&gt;Shein&lt;/span&gt; is actually magical. The fabric is light so it flows easily - and did I mention it’s less than $30? I KNOW. I’m thinking about getting another one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-palma-australia.jpg&quot; /&gt;
I discovered &lt;span class=&quot;italics&quot;&gt;Palma Australia&lt;/span&gt; while I was in Bali and it didn’t take me long to fall in love with their effortlessly feminine cuts. I basically lived in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palma-australia.com/collections/tops/products/pm1570-lollia-top&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Lollia Top&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.palma-australia.com/collections/bottoms/products/pm1591-stella-short&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Stella Shorts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-socialite.jpeg&quot; /&gt;
I actually discovered &lt;span class=&quot;italics&quot;&gt;Socialite Clothing&lt;/span&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/socialiteclothing/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; and immediately obsessed over their &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.nordstrom.com/s/socialite-lace-overlay-romper/4980314?origin=keywordsearch-personalizedsort&amp;amp;fashioncolor=BURGUNDY%20GINGER&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Lace Overlay Romper&lt;/a&gt; (yes it’s a romper!!). The lace made it romantic and feminine, but still light - the perfect date-night outfit for Bali (or anywhere tbh). PS it also comes in &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcBE&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;pink&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcBH&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;gray&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcBL&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;green&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcBP&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;ivory&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcC8&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;yellow&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcCc&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;fuchsia&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcD5&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;teal&lt;/a&gt; and &amp;lt;a href=”https://rstyle.me/~arcD7 target=”blank”“&amp;gt;coral&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-baliboatshed.jpg&quot; /&gt;
I think it’s safe to say that &lt;a href=&quot;https://baliboatshed.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Bali Boat Shed&lt;/a&gt; is a Bali staple. Located in Seminyak (underneath&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.neonpalms.com/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Neon Palms&lt;/a&gt;), this shop is filled with loads of colorful pieces. I loved almost everything from their shop, but specifically obsessed over this floral two-piece set. It’s not online yet, but once it is, I’ll be sure to update with a link!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-asha-the-label.jpg&quot; /&gt;
This dress from &lt;a href=&quot;https://ashaboutique.com.au/&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Asha the Label&lt;/a&gt; was another one of my insta-favorites. The dress was extremely light weight, had a fantastic leg slit and a gorgeous open-back. Unfortunately, it was from last season and is no longer being sold on the Asha website, but I’ve seen an extremely similar design on &lt;a href=&quot;https://rstyle.me/~arcRa&quot; target=&quot;blank&quot;&gt;Milanoo&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve never bought anything from their site before though - so shop at your own risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;space&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What look is your favorite? Are there any cool shops in Bali that I missed? I’d love to hear your thoughts below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-balistyle-lookbook.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><category term="Bali" /><summary type="html">The Ultimate Guide on what to wear and where to shop for your upcoming trip to Bali.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20180423/samisfierce-mila-lanikai.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Wanderlust Worthy Travel Quotes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/life/2018/04/22/wanderlust-worthy-quotes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wanderlust Worthy Travel Quotes" /><published>2018-04-22T00:44:03+00:00</published><updated>2018-04-22T00:44:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/life/2018/04/22/wanderlust-worthy-quotes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/life/2018/04/22/wanderlust-worthy-quotes/">&lt;p&gt;I’ll be the first to admit: thinking of instagram captions is really hard. How many times can you say ‘Getting my vitamin sea’ before your followers start rolling their eyes? Answer: less than once. When I can’t think of a witty caption (which is more often than not), I tend to go with a travel quote and I thought you guys might find them helpful too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Why do you go away? So that you can come back. So that you can see the place you came from with new eyes and extra colors. And the people there see you differently, too. Coming back to where you started is not the same as never leaving.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Terry Pratchett, A Hat Full of Sky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Surely, of all the wonders of the world, the horizon is the greatest.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Freya Stark&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171209/sun-drenched.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Now more than ever do I realize that I will never be content with a sedentary life, that I will always be haunted by thoughts of a sun-drenched elsewhere.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Isabelle Eberhardt, The Nomad: The Diaries of Isabelle Eberhardt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“She is free in her wildness, she is a wanderess, a drop of free water. She knows nothing of borders and cares nothing for rules or customs. ‘Time’ for her isn’t something to fight against. Her life flows clean, with passion, like fresh water.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Roman Payne&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I was an adventurer, but she was not an adventuress. She was a ‘wanderess.’ Thus, she didn’t care about money, only experiences - whether they came from wealth or from poverty, it was all the same to her.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Roman Payne, The Wanderess&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171209/homesick-Judith-Thurman.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Every dreamer knows that it is entirely possible to be homesick for a place you’ve never been to, perhaps more homesick than for familiar ground.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Judith Thurman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Maybe you had to leave in order to miss a place; maybe you had to travel to figure out how beloved your starting point was.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jodi Picoult, Handle with Care&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“They say no land remains to be discovered, no continent is left unexplored. But the whole world is out there, waiting, just waiting for me. I want to do things– I want to walk the rain-soaked streets of London, and drink mint tea in Casablanca. I want to wander the wastelands of the Gobi desert and see a yak. I think my life’s ambition is to see a yak. I want to bargain for trinkets in an Arab market in some distant, dusty land. There’s so much. But, most of all, I want to do things that will mean something.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lisa Ann Sandell, A Map of the Known World&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Gradually the magic of the island settled over us as gently and clingingly as pollen.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gerald Durrell, My Family and Other Animals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171209/born-to-leave-Charlotte-Eriksson.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“There’s something about arriving in new cities, wandering empty streets with no destination. I will never lose the love for the arriving, but I’m born to leave.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Charlotte Eriksson, Empty Roads &amp;amp; Broken Bottles; in search for The Great Perhaps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“And like tea dissolving in hot water, the sun dissolved in the sky… creating a velvet horizon, announcing for the stars’ night dance with the moon, the awaited joy for the wounded souls.””&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;From Bali – The Rebirth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Certainly, travel is more than the seeing of sights; it is a change that goes on, deep and permanent, in the ideas of living.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Miriam Beard&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The very basic core of a man’s living spirit is his passion for adventure. The joy of life comes from our encounters with new experiences, and hence there is no greater joy than to have an endlessly changing horizon, for each day to have a new and different sun.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Christopher McCandless&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171209/pico-iyer-travel-quote.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We travel, initially, to lose ourselves; and we travel, next to find ourselves. We travel to open our hearts and eyes hand learn more about the world than our newspapers will accommodate. We travel to bring what little we can, in our ignorance and knowledge, to those parts of the globe whose riches are differently dispersed. And we travel, in essence, to become young fools again- to slow time down and get taken in, and fall in love once more.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pico Iyer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We live in a wonderful world that is full of beauty, charm and adventure. There is no end to the adventures we can have if only we seek them with our eyes open.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jawaharal Nehru&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Most of the time, beauty lies in the simplest of things.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Winna Efendi, The Journeys&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“A journey, after all, neither begins in the instant we set out, nor ends when we have reached our door step once again. It starts much earlier and is really never over, because the film of memory continues running on inside of us long after we have come to a physical standstill. Indeed, there exists something like a contagion of travel, and the disease is essentially incurable.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ryszard Kapuściński, Travels with Herodotus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I had a desire to see something besides my own shores, if only to be content to return to them someday. If I wish to live in my native land and love her, it should not be out of ignorance.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Margaret George, Mary Queen of Scotland and The Isles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171209/eric-weiner-travel-quote.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“For me, a place unvisited is like an unrequited love. A dull ache that—try as you might to think it away, to convince yourself that she really wasn’t the right country for you—just won’t leave you in peace.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Eric Weiner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Do not stop thinking of life as an adventure. You have no security unless you can live bravely, excitingly, imaginatively, unless you can choose a challenge instead of a competence.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Eleanor Roosevelt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“For my part, I travel not to go anywhere, but to go. I travel for travel’s sake. The great affair is to move.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Robert Louis Stevenson&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We must go beyond textbooks, go out into the bypaths and untrodden depths of the wilderness and travel and explore and tell the world the glories of our journey.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;John Hope Franklin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171209/jeff-greenwald-travel-quote.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“All the above is, of course, a gross simplification. There are deeper reasons to travel – itches and tickles on the underbelly of the unconscious mind. We go where we need to go, and then try to figure out what we’re doing there.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jeff Greenwald&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Our happiest moments as tourists always seem to come when we stumble upon one thing while in pursuit of something else.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Lawrence Block&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;”Then one day, when you least expect it, the great adventure finds you.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ewan Mcgregor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The purpose of life, after all, is to live it, to taste experience to the utmost, to reach out eagerly and without fear for newer and richer experience.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Eleanor Roosevelt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We need the tonic of wildness…At the same time that we are earnest to explore and learn all things, we require that all things be mysterious and unexplorable, that land and sea be indefinitely wild, unsurveyed and unfathomed by us because unfathomable. We can never have enough of nature.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Henry David Thoreau, Walden: Or, Life in the Woods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171209/herman-melville-things-remote.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“As for me, I am tormented with an everlasting itch for things remote. I love to sail forbidden seas, and land on barbarous coasts.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Herman Melville, Moby-Dick; or, The Whale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“because he had no place he couldn’t stay in without getting tired of it and because there was nowhere to go but everywhere, keep rolling under the stars…”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jack Kerouac, On the Road&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“He found himself wondering at times, especially in the autumn, about the wild lands, and strange visions of mountains that he had never seen came into his dreams.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;J.R.R. Tolkien, The Fellowship of the Ring (The Lord of the Rings)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“She had a wild, wandering soul
but when she loved, she loved with chaos and that made all the difference.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ariana Dancu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171209/to-wander-roman-payne.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Wandering is the activity of the child, the passion of the genius; it is the discovery of the self, the discovery of the outside world, and the learning of how the self is both “at one with” and “separate from” the outside world. These discoveries are as fundamental to the soul as “learning to survive” is fundamental to the body. These discoveries are essential to realizing what it means to be human. To wander is to be alive.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Roman Payne, Europa: Limited Time Edition&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;and we laugh and laugh and
all I know is
at this moment I feel like
I can do anything I want
and be anyone I want
and go anywhere on the globe
and still call it home&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Kirsten Smith, The Geography of Girlhood&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“She would be half a planet away, floating in a turquoise sea, dancing by moonlight to flamenco guitar.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Janet Fitch, White Oleander&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We travel because we need to, because distance and difference are the secret tonic of creativity. When we get home, home is still the same. But something in our mind has been changed, and that changes everything.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jonah Lehrer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“For her the ocean was more than a dream, it was a place she needed to visit to find herself… and when she returned to the city, you could see the sun in her eyes, the wind in her hair, and taste the infinite salt on her lips.”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jose Chaves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I miss any? Let me know what your favorite travel quotes are in the comments below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;image-center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img class=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171209/samisfierce-wanderlust-travel-quotes.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Because thinking of insta captions is hard and we all need more wanderlust in our lives.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20171209/favetravelquotes.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Honestly, idk what I’m doing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/01/23/2017-idk-what-I'm-doing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Honestly, idk what I'm doing" /><published>2018-01-23T17:47:03+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T17:47:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/01/23/2017-idk-what-I'm-doing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/01/23/2017-idk-what-I'm-doing/">&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be honest with you; I feel stuck and I have no idea what I’m doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy for me to post a pretty photo on instagram, to say that everything is fine, to make a joke or to respond with “oh yeah, I’m doing surprisingly well” when people ask how I am. It’s a lot harder for me to be honest about what’s going on. It’s difficult for me to say that I feel lost or hurt, not because of what anyone might think, but because I’m scared that if I do, I’ll actually feel it - that all these emotions I’m trying so hard to ignore will come to head and I’ll be knocked over with feelings that I’m too afraid to deal with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, I don’t like to talk about hardships until everything is worked out. I wait for the happy ending before I tell the story, assuming that no one wants to hear about the chaos of the middle. During “the middle” I often find myself running away from everyone I know, busying myself with a great adventure as a distraction from what’s actually going on (as proof… I’m writing this from a villa in Bali).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always thought this was the appropriate way to deal with problems. My family was never an emotional one; despite addiction and money problems, we often put on a brave face and pretended we were just like every other white picket fence family in our neighborhood. It wasn’t until I was reading Brene Brown’s book, Rising Strong, that I realized we weren’t the only ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her book, Brown addresses this desire to skip past the middle and to wait to tell our stories until we’re on the safe side of a happy ending. At the beginning of chapter two she writes “the middle is messy, but that’s also where the magic happens.” When I read that, something clicked. I don’t watch movies or read books because of the happily ever after but because I like relating to a character’s story and going through hardships with them. I like knowing that I’m not alone or the only person that might be struggling with something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I resolved that in 2018 I would be more honest with everyone; my family, friends, followers and even myself. This is my first stab at it. I’m feeling lost and scared that I don’t know what I’m doing next or, honestly, right now. I’m tired and burnt out and just want to do something meaningful. I think I’m in the midst of (another?) quarter-life crisis and I’m not sure what to do. I’m hoping that writing this down and sharing these feelings will help me better understand myself. And, I’m also hoping that others who are going through something similar will know they’re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has anyone else felt this way or had a quarter-life crisis? I’d love to hear your stories in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;xx&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">In the midst of another quarter life crisis.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20180124/mt-agung-bali-samisfierce.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2017 A Year in Review</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/01/12/2017-year-in-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2017 A Year in Review" /><published>2018-01-12T17:47:03+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-12T17:47:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/01/12/2017-year-in-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/01/12/2017-year-in-review/">&lt;p&gt;What a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s hard to summarize a year like 2017. How do you possibly describe a year that changed you in so many ways? It was filled with pure joy - moments that left me breathless from laughter, my cheeks burning from a smile that never left my face. But, there were also moments that left me heartbroken and feeling more lost than ever. Before going into 2018, I wanted to spend some time reflecting on all the things that happened last year. And, while I’m far from having all the answers about what’s to come, I’m hoping putting this on paper will help me process some of the things that happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;The Year I Became an Entrepreneur&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about labeling this section as The Year of First Days, because that’s basically what being an entrepreneur is - constantly learning on the go and feeling like you’re building wings while hurtling off a cliff towards the ground. It’s exhilarating, scary, stressful and rewarding all at the same time. Taking an idea and forming it into a tangible company with a product and team is an amazing and unique experience, and one that I am truly grateful for. It dictated my life and gave me an identity - “entrepreneur”. I joined the elite (and potentially crazy) few who went out there and tried. And while things didn’t end the way I hoped, it was still an experience of a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;The Year I Realized I’m a Feminist&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, the word “feminist” instilled images of of short-haired women, marching around and refusing to shave. I was intimidated by their fiery passion and turned off by the negative press that feminists received. Well, in 2017, I realized that I am a feminist. I haven’t cut my hair and I definitely still shave my legs, but I realized that that doesn’t define feminism.
2017 was the year that I was exposed to the sexism that runs rampant throughout the tech and startup industry. I was on the receiving end of what felt like an endless number of inappropriate comments and unwanted advances. I heard compliment after compliment laced with shock that I, a woman, could found a company. And that was when I discovered that I was a feminist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I strongly believe that women are just as capable (if not more so) than men. And, as a result, we should receive the same amount of respect, pay, support and investment as our male counterparts. We need to lift each other up and help each other pursue our dreams and goals. We should build a community that inspires and motivates today’s children to accept and promote women leaders. Feminism isn’t just short hair and unshaved legs, it’s believing in equality and hoping for a tomorrow where girls have the same opportunities as boys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;The Year I Said Goodbye&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saying goodbye sucks. Seven years ago I said goodbye to my mom after she accidentally overdosed. This year, I said goodbye to my sister after she did the same thing. In seconds, my heart was shattered and I felt like I was thrown into a twisted version of deja vu. Losing her dragged me through a roller coaster of emotions: shock, sadness, anger, doubt, regret, acceptance and then right back through them all over again. I feel like I’ve lost a limb, a part of me that I thought would always be there. Every day I catch myself thinking about how I should call Jamie since we haven’t caught up in a while, only to be wrenched back to reality where I am overwhelmed with grief again. The realness of her passing hasn’t sunk in yet and honestly, I don’t know if I want it to. How is it fair to have a future without someone who meant so much to you?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Losing someone from an addiction brings a wealth of pain and guilt. What-ifs haunt your dreams: what if I had visited more, what if I had called her, what if I had been there? Would any of that made a difference? Could I have saved her? It’s also tinged with shame - shame from the guilt and the stigma that is associated with drug addiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the ache that I feel from losing my sister, I’ve been able to find some peace in her death. Telling my niece and nephew that she loved them, that there was nothing they could do and that it wasn’t their fault made me realize how true those words are. It helped me come to terms with losing my mom and begin to believe that I couldn’t have saved either of them. While I’m still plagued with moments of what-ifs, it’s a step in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These tragedies have also made me realize the importance of mental health. The stigma associated with depression, addiction and other mental health issues is one that our society needs to address. Hopefully by doing so people who are struggling will feel comfortable seeking help before it’s too late. If you or someone you know is struggling, I urge you to reach out. I promise, you’re not alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;The Year I Left My Startup&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Losing my sister changed me. Instantly, I regretted every moment I thought about calling and didn’t and every weekend I could have visited and chose not to. It highlighted every decision I had made and made me doubt the reasons behind them. And, while I like to try to live without regrets, I realized that I was pushing my life in the wrong direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, I had done nothing but focus on my startup. I worked endlessly and was constantly sacrificing in the name of the hustle. And while I believe that is a requirement for most startup founders, I realized it was no longer right for me. Losing my sister made me realize how little effort I had put into my relationships with family, friends and loved ones, how separated I had been from them, and how much I needed those people in my life. As a result, my drive to return to startup life disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I decided not to. I knew that returning to Well Traveled without that passion and drive would only lead to failure for the business and for my personal relationships. I decided to prioritize those relationships instead - to be a better aunt, sister, daughter, girlfriend and friend. It was a hard decision to make but I know it was the right one. There will be more companies, more ideas and more opportunities, but I only have one family.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this decision, I feel like I’ve come back down to ground zero. A huge part of me feels like I failed - failed myself, my team and everyone who believed in me. Another part of me knows that it was a huge growing experience and that I’m not the same person now as when I started. Moving away from that feeling of failure and accepting that trying and not succeeding is better than never trying at all is hard and I still, at times, have crushing moments of self-doubt. Regardless of anything, I know that I learned a lot and met many amazing people who I never would have met otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;The Year of Not Knowing What I’m Doing With My Life (again)&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of the above means that I ended the year without a job. It’s a weird feeling to not have a career, to not have a driving force for my future behind each of my actions. A big part of me feels like I’ve lost my identity. I’m no longer an entrepreneur or a marketer or a founder. I’ve realized how closely my identity has been tied to my career, and not having one makes me feel lost and self-conscious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first time in my life that I’ve decided to slow down, think and reflect on what I want out of my life. Part of me feels shame for not knowing what I’m doing, but I also know that I need time to heal. I’ve fallen to the ground, bruised and broken, and need time to figure out how to rise again. It’s been about a month since I’ve stepped away and I’m far from knowing what I want to do next. I do, however, know that I want to better prioritize those I care about, both my family and my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I look at all I accomplished in 2017, I know I couldn’t have done any of it without the support of all my loved ones. In the moment, I felt like I was making constant sacrifices but, as I look back, I know that everyone I care about was right next to me, making just as many sacrifices to help me succeed. As I start 2018, my goal is to be there for those I care about and support them in their pursuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for what 2018 holds, I have no idea. But, I’m (slowly) becoming okay with that. I’m taking time to reflect, heal, prioritize and discover what matters most to me and to spend time with loved ones. And, who knows, maybe I’ll stumble upon my next great adventure along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">2017 was a roller coaster of a year.I failed and succeeded and failed again, ending the year irreversibly changed.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20180114/2017-in-review.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">2018 Travel Bucketlist</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/01/08/2018-travel-bucketlist/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018 Travel Bucketlist" /><published>2018-01-08T22:47:03+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-08T22:47:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/01/08/2018-travel-bucketlist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/01/08/2018-travel-bucketlist/">&lt;p&gt;It’s that time of year again - time to start making resolutions that you’ll probably forget about in a month and a half. Each year I promise myself I’m going to do better, eat healthier, work out more, spend less, etc, etc. And, each year, I forget sometime in mid-February. The one thing I am good at though, is traveling. So here’s a list of the 12 places I hope to visit/do in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;1) Park City, Utah&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I kind of cheated with this one because I rang in the New Year in Park City, but it’s an absolutely amazing city. In my opinion, Utah is one of the most beautiful states in the US and I was thrilled to start the new year here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;2)Australia&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love visiting Australia. Partially because two of my best friends live here, but also because it’s an amazing country. The endless beaches are stunning and the laid back culture was exactly what I needed to kick off the year. This time, I’ll be visiting Melbourne and Wilsons Promontory National Park and I couldn’t be more excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;3) French Seychelles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a destination that has been on my list since I took French I in high school. The Seychelles are supposed to be stunning and due to global warming, might not be around much longer. I plan to cross a few destinations in Africa off my list, and the Seychelles are definitely one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;4) Capetown, South Africa&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capetown has been on my list for as long as I can remember. There are beaches, wineries and PENGUINS. This is a must-visit for me this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;5) Maine, USA&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve never been to Maine, but as I’m living on the East Coast, I would really like to check it out. Maybe I’ll eat some Maine Lobster this summer?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;6) Safari in Tanzania or Kenya&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s a visit to Africa without a safari? I’ll be planning a safari trip for May and would love to hear your suggestions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;7) See the northern lights&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This could overlap with number five, but I’ve always wanted to see the Northern Lights. Whether I pop on out to Norway or just head north, I really want to check this off this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;8) Paris, France&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to my Africa trip, I also hope to do a eurotrip this summer with my niece. The city of lights is a dream for every 16 year old (and 27 year old if I’m being honest), so I’m sure you’ll see a Parisian picnic photo in my feed sometime this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;9) Rome, Italy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rome is one of my favorite destinations in Europe. The food, the history, the culture - and did I mention the food? I’m counting down the days until I’m eating gelato and pasta in Italy again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;10) London, UK&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know, I was just in London. But, I’d like to go back! London is such an amazing history, with so much to explore. I really want to visit again this summer. Plus, I still need to visit Diagon Alley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;11) Nepal&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a place I’ve heard so many amazing things about. The natural beauty is absolutely stunning and I’ve heard the people are extremely kind. I’m hoping to pay a visit here at the end of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;12) Madagascar&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another destination on my Africa bucketlist. I think there is so much to see in Madagascar and I hope to check it out while I’m visiting Africa this summer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your travel goals for 2018? Let me know in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">2018 I'm coming for you.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20180108/travelbucketlist.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Bites at Borough Market</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/01/01/bites-at-borough-market/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bites at Borough Market" /><published>2018-01-01T22:47:03+00:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T22:47:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/01/01/bites-at-borough-market</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2018/01/01/bites-at-borough-market/">&lt;p&gt;One of the first things I did when I got to London was visit Borough Market. I had heard delicious stories of all the treats you could find, and I was hungry and ready to dive in. I can honestly say, it did not disappoint. Among the many stalls, I found my four main food groups: chocolate, wine, cheese and truffles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180102/hotchocolate.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing I wanted to try was some hot chocolate. It was a chilly December day and I knew that a good cup of hot chocolate would be just the thing to warm me up. We went to Artisan du Chocolat’s stall and got a cup of their hot chocolate with marshmallows. After the first sip, I knew I had found hot chocolate heaven. It was warm and creamy and sweet - without being overpowering. My mouth is watering just thinking about it again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180102/cheese.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a cheese fan, this place will not disappoint. There are hundreds of stalls selling all types of different cheese. But, the best part is, they all offer samples. I think I tried a hundred different cheeses, but my ABSOLUTE favorite was a mozzarella marinated in olive oil, garlic and spices. If you visit, you MUST check these guys out. Grab a baguette and prepare to enter cheese heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180102/mulledwine.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, I’m a believer that if you get an opportunity to drink mulled wine - you should take it. It’s no different at Borough Market. It was so fun to walk around trying samples at the endless number of stalls while sipping a warm glass of mulled wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180102/tastecroatia.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re a truffle fan, you’re in luck. There are dozens of truffle options at Borough Market. I sampled truffle everything: from cheese to oil to chocolate. I ended up buying a bottle of truffle olive oil from the Taste Croatia booth and am so excited to put truffle in everything when I get back home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20180102/oysters.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love oysters and there are no shortage of them at Borough Market. We visited a handful of stalls that had all different types of oysters and had a blast trying them all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you been to Borough Market? Let me know your favorite finds in the comments!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><category term="london" /><summary type="html">These are a few of my favorite things.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20180102/boroughmarket.jpg%22%5D" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Temples of Bali</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/travel/2017/12/11/bali-temples/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Temples of Bali" /><published>2017-12-11T22:47:03+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-11T22:47:03+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/travel/2017/12/11/bali-temples</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/travel/2017/12/11/bali-temples/">&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons that Bali is such a beautiful place to visit is because of the Hindu influence across the island. There are hundreds of amazing temples throughout the island, but here are my three favorites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Pura Besakih&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171212/besakih.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pura Besakih is considered the “Mother” temple in Bali. It dates back to the 14th century (although some claim as far back as the 10th!!) and is a complex of TWENTY THREE different temples. They are absolutely gorgeous and you should definitely visit on your next Bali trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Danau Tamblingan&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171212/danautamblingan.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay this one is kind of cheating because it’s more lake than temple, but there is a temple there so I’m recommending it. Go for sunrise, bring some cash and rent a canoe to take you out and see the sunrise. The mist rising from the water and the colors are absolutely stunning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6&gt;Pura Lempuyang Luhur&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/blogposts/20171212/puralempuyang.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re up for a drive, this temple is definitely worth it. It’s absolutely gorgeous and has views to die for - but it is a bit in the middle of nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to see the full list of my favorite Bali things? Check out my Google Map &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/2jUQe3b&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>{&quot;name&quot;=&gt;nil, &quot;email&quot;=&gt;&quot;samanthamruiz@gmail.com&quot;, &quot;twitter&quot;=&gt;&quot;samisfierce&quot;}</name><email>samanthamruiz@gmail.com</email></author><category term="bali" /><category term="indonesia" /><summary type="html">Bali has hundreds of breathtaking temples. Here are some of my favorites.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/%5B%22/images/blogposts/20171212/temple.JPG%22%5D" /></entry></feed>